forestforum.co.uk 2018-05-11

# LTLF Forest Forum - Privacy Policy

## COMMITMENT TO YOUR PRIVACY 

This site is owned and operated by NG Interactive Ltd. Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. We want to make your online experience satisfying and safe. 

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it. 

We invite you to contact us if you have questions about this policy. You may contact us by mail at the following address: 

    NG Interactive Ltd, Mercury House, Shipstones Business Centre, New Basford, Nottingham, NG7 7FN

Or, you may contact us by [eMail](http://www.forestforum.co.uk/sendmessage.php) or via Private Message.

**Additional Information** : [Terms of Service](http://www.forestforum.co.uk/info.php?do=terms "Terms of Service")

## INFORMATION THIS SITE GATHERS AND TRACKS 

Forestforum.co.uk gathers two types of information about users: 

Information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions. These are voluntary submissions to receive our electronic newsletters, to participate in our message boards or forums, to email a friend, and from participation in polls and surveys: 

Information Forestforum.co.uk gathers through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites. This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to help our advertisers and sponsors better understand the demographics of our audience. Because Forestforum.co.uk derives its revenue mainly from sponsorships, advertisement and / or donations, providing such aggregated demographic data is essential to keeping our service free to users. Under no circumstances does NG Interactive Ltd divulge any information about an individual user to a third party. 

NG Interactive Ltd Gathers User Information In The Following Processes: 

**Optional Voluntary Information**

We offer the following free services, which require some type of voluntary submission of personal information by users: 

1\. Electronic newsletters (Dispatches) 

We will offer a free electronic newsletter to users.Forestforum.co.uk gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page. Users can also subscribe to the newsletters at the time of registration. 

2\. Message boards/forums 

Users of the site's Message Boards and Forums must register separately for these services (both are free of charge) in order to post messages, although they needn't register to visit the site. During registration the user is required to supply a username, password, and email address. 

3\. "E-mail this to a friend" Service 

Our site users can choose to electronically forward a link, page, or documents to someone else by clicking "e-mail this to a friend". The user must provide their email address, as well as that of the recipient. This information is used only in the case of transmission errors and, of course, to let the recipient know who sent the email. The information is not used for any other purpose. 

4\. Polling 

We may offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what our audience thinks about important issues. Opinions or other responses to polls are aggregated and are not identifiable to any particular user. Forestforum.co.uk may use a system to "tag" users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users. 

5\. Surveys 

Forestforum.co.uk may occasionally conduct user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our sponsors, advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party. 

**Children**

We will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent. 

**Usage tracking**

Forestforum.co.uk tracks user traffic patterns throughout all of our site. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. NG Interactive Ltd does break down overall usage statistics according to a user's domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser). 

Forestforum.co.uk sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in our Search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. 

**Cookies**

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Forestforum.co.uk uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above). Our advertising system is maintained by google and the following applies:- · Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website. · Google's use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet. · Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the advertising opt-out page. 

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you do need cookies to participate actively in message boards, forums, polling and surveys. 

**Affiliate Marketing**

Our website contains some affiliate marketing links, which means we get paid commission on sales of those products or services we write about. Our content is not influenced by advertisers or affiliate partnerships. We use a 3rd Party to enable these affiliate partnerships. You can read their [Privacy Policy](http://skimlinks.com/privacy-policy#users) and find more information on [the cookies they use](http://skimlinks.com/user-cookies).

## USE OF INFORMATION

NG Interactive Ltd uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users. 

As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, surveys, message boards, and forums. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. NG Interactive Ltd never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners. 

When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters. 

NG Interactive Ltd creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because we don't track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser or sponsor will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. We will not disclose any information about any individual user except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

## SHARING OF THE INFORMATION

NG Interactive ltd uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand our audience's demographics. This is essential to keeping our service free. We will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

## OPT-OUT POLICY

We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include: 

Opting not to register to receive our electronic newsletters. 

Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas, which completely alleviates the need to gather any personally identifiable information from our users 

## YOUR CONSENT

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by NG Interactive Ltd. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

We collect the following information: 

  1. Click-stream data 
  2. HTTP protocol elements 
  3. Search terms 
  4. User's Name 
  5. Computer information 

At the user's option, we may also collect the following data: 

  1. Birth Date 
  2. Email Address

This data will be used for the following purposes: 

  1. Completion and support of the current activity. 
  2. Web site and system administration. 
  3. Research and development. 

This data will be used by ourselves and our agents. 

The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected: 

Data collected from all Web users: access logs, and search strings (if entered). 

At the user's option, we will collect the following data: 

  1. HTTP cookies 

This data will be used for the following purposes: 

  1. Research and development. 
  2. One-time tailoring. 

This data will be used by ourselves and our agents. 

The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected: 

## COOKIES

Cookies are used to track visitors to our site, so we can better understand what portions of our site best serve you.

Cookies are a technology which can be used to provide you with tailored information from a Web site. A cookie is an element of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. 

Our site makes use of cookies. Cookies are used for the following purposes: 

  1. User targeting 
  2. Research and development
